<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethan Madison</title>
    <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ethan Madison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ethan Madison 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 17:29:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ethanmad.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Earning my A in Fencing</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/A-in-Epee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 17:29:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/A-in-Epee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started fencing epee competitively in the Spring of 2012 at LAIFC, where I was very fortunate to train with some of the best fencers and coaches in the world.
Through many intense practices and about forty tournaments, I progressed very quickly.
The U.S. Fencing Association uses a rating system where beginners are unrated and more experienced fencers are rated from E to A, where A is the highest rating.
Within a year of training, I earned an E and a C.
A year later, I earned a B at a tournament at my club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up not fencing during my senior year of high school because of school and other obligations taking up my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got to Michigan, I decided I had to start fencing again.
Fortunately for me, the University of Michigan Fencing Club is one of the top college clubs in the country, so I can practice regularly and compete at a high level.
Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to maintain much of my skill and even improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I competed at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://askfred.net/Results/results.php?tournament_id=30100&#34;&gt;Todd Curn Memorial tournament&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Royal Arts Fencing Academy in Columbus, OH; won the gold medal; and finally earned an A rating after coming so close so many times!
Below is a playlist of YouTube videos with my final three elimination bouts (starting with the best bout&amp;ndash;the semifinal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/X6ZHHLDck30?list=PLwfXW8DKOrg1cLm2BXwatRqPhEH5_jcGH&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last two bouts were against A rated fencers, both of whom are generally regarded as some of the best fencers in the area.
In particular, my semifinal bout was one of the hardest fights I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had.
I was at one point down 9-13 (these bouts go to 15) and had to outscore my opponent 6-1 to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The win was easily one of the most gratifying experiences in my life&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the other side enough times that finally being on the winning side felt beyond amazing&amp;ndash;and it took all of my determination and focus to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing Drums on Record</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/drum-recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:28:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/drum-recording/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My magnum opus in drumming: three mastered tracks from my recording sessions with Marco Moir. See below for the songs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;backstory&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fourth grade, I decided I was done playing piano and wanted to pick up a new instrument.
I wanted to play something cool; an instrument I could join a band with.
My dad played drums in his youth and we had a drum set in the house, so I was drawn towards the drums.
I joined my elementary school&amp;rsquo;s orchestral music program and began playing snare drum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple years later, I got more serious about drumming and got a private teacher.
That year, I played drum set in a band with some friends at one or two school concerts and continued playing in the school&amp;rsquo;s orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Harvard-Westlake, I continued playing in the orchestra and was the main drummer during the symphony&amp;rsquo;s back-to-back Heritage Festival Gold medals (we competed in Anaheim and Chicago&amp;rsquo;s renowned &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symphony_Center&#34;&gt;Orchestra Hall&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In tenth grade, I dropped classical music in favor of jazz; a genre of music I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; enjoyed!
I joined the jazz program at school and participated in the Rhythm Section and Jazz Ensemble through my senior year.
Playing drum set daily allowed me to improve over those three years and got me to the point where I can sit and just play with most music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recording&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer, with my teacher and mentor Ray Mehlbaum, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on prerparing a selection of songs that represent my musical taste and drumming style that I could record at the end of summer.
I picked three songs from long before my time; one blues, one rock, and one jazz fusion; each featuring amazing guitarists and drummers: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_House_(song)&#34;&gt;Red House&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Jimi Hendrix), &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunshine_of_Your_Love&#34;&gt;Sunshine of Your Love&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Cream), &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Freeway-Jam/dp/B00136O3J4&#34;&gt;Freeway Jam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Jeff Beck).
I played drums on and Marco Moir played guitar, bass, and keyboard on; sang; and mixed the following tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tracks&#34;&gt;Tracks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/221074184&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/221074548&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/221073204&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thank you to my teacher, inspirator, and friend Ray Mehlbaum for helping me prepare and arranging the session and to Marco Moir, my amazingly talented partner and producer who worked tirelessly to get these tracks they way they are..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperTyper</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/HyperTyper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 21:04:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/HyperTyper/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ethanmad/HyperTyper/master/res/hypertyper%20128.png&#34; alt=&#34;HyperTyper&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HyperTyper is a tool to help those who can&amp;rsquo;t type compete in typing competitions, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://typeracer.com/&#34; title=&#34;Real-time racing against real people.&#34;&gt;TypeRacer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://10fastfingers.com/&#34; title=&#34;Testing and competitions with daily leaderboards.&#34;&gt;10FastFingers&lt;/a&gt;.
  I aim to reduce discrimination against non- or transtypers from heterotypers by eliminating the social construct that is the keyboard. Switching layouts or not knowing how to type should not mean you have to repeatedly feel the pain of losing.
  The layout of a keyboard is a social construct created by the evil and discriminatory typewriter organization Remington and people who do not conform to the keyboard do not deserve to be punished for their noncomfornance.&lt;br /&gt;
  Further, the privileged elitist typers like Sean Wrona who were unfairly born with the innate ability to type at ludicrous speeds do not deserve to win every competition in which they compete just because they practice typing for hours every day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With HyperTyper, this unjust discrimination has been put to an end; anyone can now be a HyperTyper and compete &amp;ldquo;fairly&amp;rdquo; even if they &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captain_Hook/&#34; title=&#34;Do you like codfish?&#34;&gt;lost a hand to a croc&lt;/a&gt; or suffer from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/anonymous/bd15723d8e9118c1ea48&#34; title=&#34;gerangfelmHEALPAgerna!!&#34;&gt;horrible hand spasms&lt;/a&gt;.
  Equal opportunnity for all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 11th grade, I had a second-semester project for my Design and Data Structures class in which I was allowed to make really whatever I wanted.
  Having never made a Chrome extension and being interested in breaking leaderboards, I decided to make a TypeRacer cheat extension after seeing some friends race on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a few weeks, I built HyperTyper in a few steps.
  I first learned how to edit the page DOM with JQuery and figured out how to input text into a text field.
  The next step was figuring out how to access the text field, given that TypeRacer assigns unique names (seemingly random strings) to their input boxes.
  Next, I had to make the actual Chrome extension, which involves a manifest file and a background script to figure out when the extension should display.
  Because the extension is only useful on a few sites, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the icon to always show up; instead, the extension only shows up and can only be activated on the supported sites.
  At some point, I decided that I did not want HyperTyper injecting JQuery into every page.
  Being a JavaScript noob, transitioning the DOM manipulation code to pure JS was difficult and took time, but definitely worth it given the benefit of reduced resource use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, to make the project more widely usable (net necessarily useful given it&amp;rsquo;s function and purpose), I made it simple to add compatability with new (but functionally similar) websites by feeding in two arrays with the identifiers (either a name or class) of the text to type and the input field. Because the identifiers are either names or classes, HyperTyper knows which to expect based on the website it&amp;rsquo;s being used on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I added compatability for all the sites I could find, I uploaded the extension to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hypertyper/emlnlmijjaghanenmpdjdckanpdinpgn?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;Click install!&#34;&gt;Chrome Web Store&lt;/a&gt; and also figured out how to make a &lt;a href=&#34;javascript:(function()%7Bfor(var%20textOptions%3D%5B%22nonHideableWords%20unselectable%22%2C%22cw-QuotePanel-textToTypePanel%22%2C%22row1%22%2C%22practiceText%22%2C%22textData%22%5D%2CinputBoxOptions%3D%5B%22txtInput%22%2C%22cw-TypedinputBox%20race-go%22%2C%22form-control%22%2C%22tentry%22%2C%22userData%22%5D%2Cwebsite%3D-1%2CclassOrId%3D-1%2Cw%3D0%3Bw%3CtextOptions.length%3Bw%2B%2B)if(null!%3Ddocument.getElementsByClassName(textOptions%5Bw%5D)%5B0%5D)%7Bwebsite%3Dw%3BclassOrId%3D0%3Bbreak%7Delse%20if(null!%3Ddocument.getElementById(textOptions%5Bw%5D))%7Bwebsite%3Dw%3BclassOrId%3D1%3Bbreak%7Dif(-1%3Cwebsite%26%26-1%3CclassOrId)%7Bvar%20text%3B0%3D%3D%3DclassOrId%3Ftext%3Ddocument.getElementsByClassName(textOptions%5Bwebsite%5D)%5B0%5D.textContent%3A1%3D%3D%3DclassOrId%26%26(text%3Ddocument.getElementById(textOptions%5Bwebsite%5D).textContent)%3Bvar%20numWords%3Dtext.split(%22%20%22).length%2CinputBox%3Bnull!%3Ddocument.getElementsByClassName(inputBoxOptions%5Bwebsite%5D)%5B0%5D%3FinputBox%3Ddocument.getElementsByClassName(inputBoxOptions%5Bwebsite%5D)%5B0%5D%3Anull!%3Ddocument.getElementById(inputBoxOptions%5Bwebsite%5D)%26%26(inputBox%3Ddocument.getElementById(inputBoxOptions%5Bwebsite%5D))%3Bi%3D0%3Bvar%20addWord%3Dfunction()%7Bif(!(i%3E%3DnumWords))if(word%3Dtext.split(%22%20%22)%5Bi%2B%2B%5D%2C3%3D%3D%3Dwebsite)for(inputBox.value%3D%22%22%2Cl%3D0%3Bl%3Cword.length%3Bl%2B%2B)inputBox.value%2B%3Dword%5Bl%5D%3Belse%20inputBox.value%3Dword%7D%3BaddWord()%3Bwindow.onkeyup%3Dfunction(a)%7B32%3D%3D(a.keyCode%3Fa.keyCode%3Aa.which)%26%26addWord()%7D%7D%7D)()&#34; title=&#34;Drag to your bookmarks bar!&#34;&gt;HyperTyper bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; so as not to leave out users of other browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;accomplishments&#34;&gt;Accomplishments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of what I would consider the project&amp;rsquo;s successes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blowing past opponents and high scores is a piece of cake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scores above 500 WPM are very possible even with just a single keyboard (much higher scores attainable with scripts and multiple keyboards)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winning is fun and there are a lot of different strategies (no mercy, wait until the last second, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smashing the spacebar is fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works on all platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t require script to be inputted via console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works on multiple sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be installed to the operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;failures&#34;&gt;Failures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HyperTyper still has the following issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can&amp;rsquo;t get around the CAPTCHA on TypeRacer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smashing the spacebar is tiring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulating a user space bar press is impossible in a Chrome Extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only works on sites that take input word-by-word rather than letter-by-letter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes it works, sometimes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vulnerable to breaking if a website changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, HyperTyper was fun to make and is still fun to use sometimes. I think my brother gets more use out of it than I do.
  Suprisingly, there are over 1650 users  of HyperTyper! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how or why people find the extension, but maybe some people really do want to cheat in races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HyperTyper was a great learning experience involving Chrome extensions and JavaScript and it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious to see people&amp;rsquo;s reactions when the see my scores of over 500 WPM.
  Sometimes, just sometimes, people think it&amp;rsquo;s actually humanely possible to achieve that kind of score.
  This project has also spawned a new competition: spacebar mashing (or writing a script to press space).
  On &lt;a href=&#34;http://typingspeedcontest.com&#34; title=&#34;Yours truly on top.&#34;&gt;Typing Speed Contest&lt;/a&gt;, the ranking is really determined by who can press the spacebar the fastest because all the top scores are the result of HyperTyper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, if you do end up using HyperTyper, please type responsibly. Don&amp;rsquo;t make little kids cry when they&amp;rsquo;re just trying to learn to type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hypertyper/emlnlmijjaghanenmpdjdckanpdinpgn?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;Click install!&#34;&gt;HyperTyper on Chrome Web Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethanmad.com/HyperTyper&#34;&gt;HyperTyper Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad/HyperTyper&#34;&gt;HyperTyper on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Ethan Madison.
I was born and raised in Los Angeles and am currently a student at the University of Michigan&amp;ndash;Ann Arbor.
I &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad&#34;&gt;write code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethanmad.com/post/drum-recording&#34;&gt;play drums&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethanmad.com/post/A-in-Epee&#34;&gt;fence&lt;/a&gt; for fun.
My PGP fingerprint is &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/ethanmad#show-public&#34;&gt;53525058FB8695B7&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-this-site&#34;&gt;What is this site?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website serves as a blog and project showcase. I plan on writing up summaries after completing a project in addition to normal blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which is coincidentally also the name of &lt;a href=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Wo1P8Pck7Y-dUEF0QkHxT91OYTKuYaBIJ5gqdju4SWjlclvOJVFta-0loSQ6XO3oP6CXQzCsMhk2wJ6Res98ckRn0uz47In18vWXYe2qd0RAZW6AzBxTHO8BkoIconyuW4MnsxQjkjqsDmHEjzdkSuMId2S0V2XNOdIf8vnNb3bLKg4giRTAlQPB4lTtj_gebBro4KZ5nEHKroI3MlJL2x4H6cQ2j7-ukLeHoCjmhOzZiPy439y2jmvi5pygugxAFjw7iER7Qv8OdxtOPVwX56n9fpptnGZpdTT1HIQSNXoF47Vb9Co80uEH1GlaEh-tpzY9CrAXmIJYgoxXJtn-0eRkbcEOtU-toi8byQHq5pXbmMgcZk70rXw91qcbqahimJq7_nRYqWE-JTnYHhyqbp38KtlpshpjYY55V2rT-GEyyUYNMpM90xJq1kYMP35ua7r86KcF5NUpIU0UW8G-Y6PHIlRDvLP9TyD79XB13GMMlP9UPx1p9GDBzeyyD58k1fnPddPoLXCJDx3pBleaK1skhA2wQgBmA9llAEjSFec6V83RYdFpi8n5FGMfVLXRRQV8=s1278-no&#34; title=&#34;A picture of him inspecting my browser history.&#34;&gt;my dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website&amp;rsquo;s source is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad/hugo_site&#34;&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethanmad.com/projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; for a list of my projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;connect&#34;&gt;Connect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact me or find me through the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@ethanmad.com&#34; title=&#34;The best way to reach me.&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/+ethanmad&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_ethanmad&#34; title=&#34;Not really used, but here it is.&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linkedin.com/in/ethanmadison&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/u/ethanmad&#34; title=&#34;I mostly lurk.&#34;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/users/2264460/ethanmad&#34; title=&#34;I _clearly_ have no idea what I&#39;m doing.&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/ethanmad&#34; title=&#34;Where I drop my tracks and share my friends&#39;.&#34;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/ethanmad&#34; title=&#34;Find my PGP keys here.&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I haven&amp;rsquo;t listed a service you want to connect with me on, search for &lt;code&gt;ethanmad&lt;/code&gt; and you may find me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;current&#34;&gt;Current&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ethanmad.com&#34;&gt;This site&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m still working on adding content to this site and developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad/vienna&#34;&gt;its theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://umich.edu/~fencing&#34;&gt;University of Michigan Fencing Club Website&lt;/a&gt; (Spring 2016 - present): I became webmaster in 2016 and realized that the site was difficult to update, edit, and keep consistent. I rebuilt the site Summer 2016 using Hugo to allow for easy updates, consistent theming, templating, and easy contributions from teammates. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/UM-Fencing/UMFC-Website&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/UM-Fencing/club-theme&#34;&gt;Hugo club-theme&lt;/a&gt; (Summer 2016 - present): The Hugo theme and layout template for the UMFC website and suitable for any student organization or club&amp;rsquo;s website. A heavily modified fork of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/key-amb/hugo-theme-bootie-docs&#34;&gt;key-amb/bootie-docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;past&#34;&gt;Past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad/chromeos-resize&#34;&gt;chromeos-resize&lt;/a&gt; (Summer 2016): A script to easily resize partitions on Chrome OS devices, typically used for dual-booting. Built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ehegnes&#34;&gt;Eric Hegnes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheWashingtonRedskins/Hackatron&#34;&gt;Hackatron&lt;/a&gt; (Septermber 2015): Real-time in person help and mentorship tool built for hackathons, offices, and schools. Built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paralin&#34;&gt;Christian Stewart&lt;/a&gt; at MHacks 6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZvAWzwYOl4o&#34;&gt;Screencast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hwcomputerscience/ihw-android&#34;&gt;iHW-Android&lt;/a&gt; (Fall 2014 - Spring 2015): A schedule app for Harvard-Westlake. I&amp;rsquo;m the 2014-15 developer and am almost finished with my AppCompat redesign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheWashingtonRedskins/LivingPlanet&#34;&gt;LivingPlanet&lt;/a&gt; (December 2014): My submission to and a finalist in the 2014 Koding Global Hackathon. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://meteor.com&#34;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt; site built demonstrating issues on our planet. Built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paralin&#34;&gt;Christian Stewart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jameslennon321&#34;&gt;James Lennon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thesafo&#34;&gt;Jake Saferstein&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dwoldenberg1&#34;&gt;David Woldenberg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openpad.github.io&#34;&gt;openpad&lt;/a&gt; (Fall 2014): A platform for using Andoid &amp;amp; iOS devices as input devices on C++-capable devices. Built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jameslennon321&#34;&gt;James Lennon&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thesafo&#34;&gt;Jake Saferstein&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW Java networking projects (Fall 2014): &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/ethanmad/ChatServer&#34;&gt;ChatServer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad/HTTPServer&#34;&gt;HTTPServer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethanmad.com/En-Garde&#34;&gt;En Garde&lt;/a&gt; (Summer 2014): An Android fencing scorekeeper built to be fast, pretty, and functional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethanmad.com/post/HyperTyper&#34;&gt;HyperTyper&lt;/a&gt; (Spring 2014): A typing &amp;ldquo;aid&amp;rdquo; (it&amp;rsquo;s a tool to cheat in games like &lt;a href=&#34;http://typeracer.com&#34;&gt;TypeRacer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ethanmad.com/coo-mc&#34;&gt;Coo&lt;/a&gt;: A Minecraft escape map I built with &lt;a href=&#34;http://tom.ethanmad.com&#34;&gt;my brother Tommy&lt;/a&gt; some years ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything else on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethanmad&#34;&gt;my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Current as of 2017-01-02.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>