<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethan Madison</title>
    <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/tags/fencing/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ethan Madison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ethan Madison 2016</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ethanmad.com/tags/fencing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Earning my A in Fencing</title>
      <link>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/A-in-Epee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 17:29:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ethanmad.com/post/A-in-Epee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started fencing epee competitively in the Spring of 2012 at LAIFC, where I was very fortunate to train with some of the best fencers and coaches in the world.
Through many intense practices and about forty tournaments, I progressed very quickly.
The U.S. Fencing Association uses a rating system where beginners are unrated and more experienced fencers are rated from E to A, where A is the highest rating.
Within a year of training, I earned an E and a C.
A year later, I earned a B at a tournament at my club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up not fencing during my senior year of high school because of school and other obligations taking up my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got to Michigan, I decided I had to start fencing again.
Fortunately for me, the University of Michigan Fencing Club is one of the top college clubs in the country, so I can practice regularly and compete at a high level.
Because of this, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to maintain much of my skill and even improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I competed at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://askfred.net/Results/results.php?tournament_id=30100&#34;&gt;Todd Curn Memorial tournament&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Royal Arts Fencing Academy in Columbus, OH; won the gold medal; and finally earned an A rating after coming so close so many times!
Below is a playlist of YouTube videos with my final three elimination bouts (starting with the best bout&amp;ndash;the semifinal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/X6ZHHLDck30?list=PLwfXW8DKOrg1cLm2BXwatRqPhEH5_jcGH&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last two bouts were against A rated fencers, both of whom are generally regarded as some of the best fencers in the area.
In particular, my semifinal bout was one of the hardest fights I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had.
I was at one point down 9-13 (these bouts go to 15) and had to outscore my opponent 6-1 to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The win was easily one of the most gratifying experiences in my life&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the other side enough times that finally being on the winning side felt beyond amazing&amp;ndash;and it took all of my determination and focus to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>